Contact

+79069125317 (Mobile) jurbat@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ybatenko (LinkedIn) github.com/svenyurgensson (Portfolio)

Top Skills

Photoshop

Illustrator

After Effects

Languages

Russian (Native or Bilingual)
English (Professional Working)

Certifications

Try Docker

Functional Programming Principles in Scala

Programming Languages

Yury Batenko

Backend developer: RoR, Go, RabbitMQ, PostgreSQL

Krasnoyarsk, Krasnoyarsk Krai, Russia

Summary

Developer with 15+ years of experience, proficient in all aspects of web development, from crafting javascript code to optimizing web server and database performance. Worked with a wide range of programming languages, platforms, and databases.

Ruby: since 2003

Go language

Ruby on Rails: since 2007

Sinatra, WebMachine, Rack for building APIs

Rspec, MiniTest

Redis, Postgresql, MySql, MongoDB

RabbitMQ

SASS, SCSS, HAML, Slim

JavaScript, Jquery, React

Proficient in developing complex WebExtension browser plugins

C: 6 years (embedded devices)

Have a few pet or production projects: Go, Erlang, Elixir Familiar with Clojure, Scala, Lisp, ASM86, ASM Z80, ASM PIC16 Facebook API, Google API, LinkedIn API, Github API, Twitter API Capistrano, Mina, Ansible

Good knowledge of the technologies around computers running Mac OS X and Linux. Strong experience in scaling Ruby on Rails applications, using Nginx servers. Good understanding of ActiveRecord and Ruby on Rails general internals. Experienced in deploying Ruby on Rails applications into production environment on Unix-based servers with Capistrano, Ansible.

Experienced in UI design, building simple, clean and effective websites that are easy to navigate and use.

Good business knowledge and excellent creative source of ideas and solutions to both technical and business challenges. Good skills in working with people and being agile. Can build a new team or join an existing one.

Skills:

Linux, Nginx, passenger, Ruby, Rails, REST, RSpec, BDD, Go, JavaScript, DOM, Object oriented programming, jQuery, AJAX, CSS2/3, cross-browser markup.

Strong knowledge of PostgreSQL, MongoDB. Agile web development, Git, Github, Basecamp.

Base knowledge of Erlang, Elixir – have a few finished pet projects. Main interests: designing and implementing RESTfull APIs, server-side services, long-lived server application, high load.

Experience

Evrone

Ruby on Rails Engineer February 2024 - September 2024 (8 months)

As a Ruby On Rails developer works on Evrone projects

Региональные Информационные Системы Web Application Developer December 2022 - December 2023 (1 year 1 month) Krasnoyarsk, Krasnoyarsk Krai, Russia

Доработка и сопровождение региональной школьной системы дневников и учета https://kiasuo.ru

Разработка API, работа с внешними сервисами, интеграция с ЕСИА. Доработки и сопровождение систем психологического тестирования https://demo.soctest.ru/

Paneco.com Singapore
Project Lead Developer
March 2021 - November 2022 (1 year 9 months)
Singapore

Work on large spree codebase. Tuning database, API, migrated spree from ver 3 to 4.

Business Class Consolidator Back End Developer October 2020 - January 2021 (4 months)

- develop and implement software based on requirements and user needs
- · follow estimations and time limitations

Self-employed Software Engineer April 2020 - October 2020 (7 months)

sdclabs.com
Senior Software Engineer
February 2017 - March 2020 (3 years 2 months)
Krasnoyarsk Territory, Russian Federation

Developing backends and partly frontend for several products.

API for mobile

Documentation

DB scheme designing

Amazon RDS, Redshift, EC infrastructure

DobroTAO

Tech leader

April 2015 - February 2017 (1 year 11 months)

Krasnoyarsk Territory, Russian Federation

Software and hardware architect, mentoring juniors

Develop internal CRM products, customers database, payment and billing service. Give to our customers ability to buy items from giant China webshops like taobao.com, tmall.com and 1688.com.

Build browser plugins using contemporary ES6 with unique features: turbomode, online opaque shop translations, shops ratings, basket, favorites. Developed API using go language for fast and reliable access browser plugins for authentication, session management and receiving and storing customer's basket.

earthTV network GmbH

Senior engineer

January 2013 - April 2016 (3 years 4 months)

Developing APIs for public and internal services;

Writing video streaming server Go, Mongodb GridFS;

Writing specifications and documentations.

Performance tuning, optimisations.

Mediasota.ru RubyOnRails developer February 2010 - February 2014 (4 years 1 month) Krasnoyarsk

As entrepreneur and lead developer have built a few local Krasnoyarsk web sites, all based on Ruby on Rails 3.2:

http://ikr.ru/

http://ivshein.ru/

http://svetotehnica.ru/

http://puppet24.ru

and few others.

Canadel

Krasnoyarsk

Project leader, architect December 2011 - May 2013 (1 year 6 months)

Remote work for German company Canadel.

Developing: internal application

http://easycreate.heroku.com/

as part of DumboCMS platform (created by other Canadel developers) http://ebike.de/ also for Canadel, platform for easy integration with http://affili.net network utilizing http API, have written few gems for this platform. As well as http://dunkleschokolade.com/ site based on the same platform. Rails 3.2.8

NoName

Lead developer

August 2011 - December 2011 (5 months)

Krasnoyarsk

As a project leader of developers team have develop internal CRM for world wide farmacy company Nycomed, used for marketing investigations, provide SMS quizzes between target customers (>30000 customers, >48000 retail outlets). Rails 3.1, PostgreSQL, redis, resque, coffeescript.

Orwik

Middle developer March 2011 - September 2011 (7 months)

Krasnoyarsk

Middle developer as a part of distributed team.

Have implemented new features, support legacy Ruby On Rails code base.

Education

Synergy University

Bachelor's degree, Computer and Information Sciences and Support Services · (September 2019 - May 2023)

Siberian State Aerospace University, Krasnoyarsk, bachelor of IT, IT · (1993 - 1996)

Technical College

Bachelor's degree, IT specialization · (1988 - 1993)